brain a minimal esoteric programming language designed to make
Brain fuck 一种最小的深奥编程语言，旨在让
your brain hurt it's turing complete but not designed to build actual software
您的大脑受到伤害 它图灵完备，但并非旨在构建实际软件
it's more like a work of art that challenges the status quo it was created
它更像是一件挑战现状的艺术品 它是
in 1993 by swiss physics student urban mueller where the goal was to create a
由瑞士物理专业的学生urban mueller于1993年创建的，目标是 为了创建一种
language with the smallest possible compiler it was built for the amiga 2.0
具有尽可能小的编译器的语言，它是为 amiga 2.0
operating system and the compiler weighs in at under 200 bytes a brain program
操作系统构建的，编译器的重量低于 200 字节，大脑程序
starts with a 30 000 byte one dimensional array all values are
以 30 000 字节的一维数组开始，所有值都
initialized to zero then it provides a movable pointer that you can manipulate
初始化为零，然后它提供了一个可移动的 可以
with eight different commands use angle brackets to move the pointer left or
使用八种不同命令操作的指针 使用尖括号一次将指针向左或
right by one cell at a time then increment or decrement the value in a
向右移动一个单元格，然后
cell using plus or minus use a period to output the byte at the pointer's current
使用加号或减号递增或递减单元格中的值 使用句点在指针的当前位置输出字节
location or use a comma to accept input and store it at the pointer's current
或使用逗号接受输入并将其存储在指针的当前
location and finally use opening and closing brackets to create a loop notice
位置，最后使用左括号和右括号创建循环 注意
how brain fog doesn't require silly things like variables functions and
脑雾如何不需要变量函数和类等愚蠢的东西
classes to get started with brain delete your operating system and install
来开始使用脑他妈的删除你的操作系统并安装
amiga os then create a file ending in bf which stands for brain fog any
amiga os然后创建一个以bf结尾的文件代表脑雾任何
characters that are not the aid i mentioned previously will be ignored as
不是我提到的帮助的字符以前将被忽略
a comment at this point we have an array with thirty thousand eight bit numbers
为注释此时我们有一个包含三万八位数的数组
all set to 0. to say hi mom we'll need to set each number to its corresponding
全部设置为 0. 说嗨妈妈我们需要将每个数字设置为其对应的
ascii character we can increment the first cell then enter a loop with an
ascii 字符我们可以增加第一个单元格然后输入 循环
opening bracket for each iteration of the loop we'll decrement that current
的每次迭代都有一个带左括号的循环我们将当前
cell by 5 then use an angle bracket to move one cell to the right we'll
单元格减 5，然后使用尖括号将一个单元格向右移动，我们
increment that cell by three then move back to the left and close the loop the
将该单元格增加 3，然后移回左侧并关闭 循环
loop will continue until the original cell goes back to zero at which point it
循环将继续，直到原始单元格回到零，此时
will exit we now have a value of 103 at index one we can move the pointer to it
它将退出我们现在在索引 1 处的值为 103，我们可以将指向它的
increment it to 104 then use a period to output it that corresponds to the letter
指针移至 104，然后使用句点输出 i  t 对应于字母
h and ascii we can increment it again to get 105 which corresponds to the letter
h 和 ascii 我们可以再次增加它以获得对应于字母
i now we continue this process of manipulating memory like caveman until
i 的 105 现在我们继续这个像穴居人一样操纵内存的过程，直到
we output all the characters that we need now to run your code use
我们输出我们现在需要的所有字符来运行你的代码使用权 -
right-click copy and paste it into one of the many online interpreters
单击复制并将其粘贴到众多在线口译员之一
congratulations you just said hi to your mom and brain this has been brain
恭喜您刚刚向您的妈妈和大脑他妈的这已经
in 100 seconds if you want to see more brain content on this channel
是 100 秒内的大脑他妈的如果您想在此频道上看到更多的大脑他妈的内容，请
make sure to hit the like button and subscribe thanks for watching and i will
确保点击喜欢按钮 并订阅感谢收看，我会
see you in the next one
在下一个看到你